Oktoar.
[Music]
Wearin
again.
Foreish.
Australia.
form
Save the day.
foreign.
Fore!
[Music]
Foreign! Foreign!
Right.
Foreignech.
foreign.
[Music]
forchech.
Victoria.
Special thanks in English to Aaron
Sailor, engineer Aon Sailor, which is
the director and principal engineer of
ICM
and he will talk about a framework for
coastal resilience.
[Music]
for
Victoria.
Shalom Victoria.
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
Fore
[Music]
speech.
for
[Music]
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
Foreington.
Um,
[Music]
Charlie
forchech.
[Music]
foreign.
Erington.
forchech.
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
Come upon me.
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
[Music]
for
speech.
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
for
Charlan.
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
Dear
Foreignch
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
speech. Foreign speech.
Fore
speech.
forchech.
Step to step by step.
forch.
foreign.
Victoria.
[Music]
Okay.
foreign
We are gonna
go
on
Michelle. Michelle.
Okay.
[Music]
Joseph.
Arlington. ington.
[Music]
to the Victoria.
I'll switch to English now.
We'll move now to our next speaker, Mr.
Aon Sailor. He's the managing director
of ICM and he will talk with us about
framework for coastal resilience. This
talk will be for 40 minutes including
questions. Please Mr. Sailor.
Hey, morning everyone. Thanks for having
me. Um my name is Aaron from
International Coastal Management. Um
we're based here on the Gold Coast in
Australia. That's a picture of the Gold
Coast you can see. Um beautiful place um
halfway up the east coast of Australia.
So just a quick intro who we are. Um so
we're called International Coastal
Management ICM. Been around for nearly
45 years. Um even though we're based in
Australia, we do projects kind of all
over the world.
um currently doing projects in
Australia, California, Zanzibar,
Tanzania, some around the Middle East,
um something in Europe at the moment.
So, we're going to get um around the
world.
Um just a little bit about what this
talk is. I'm going to talk about our
approach to coastal protection and
resilience. And you know there's not one
right or wrong answer of how to do the
approach. This is just the way that we
approach it. And I understand you know
every site is different and there's no
one solution that's perfect or fits
every you know coastline. But um this is
the kind of philosophy that we have when
we approach it. We say it's kind of like
working with nature but really it's not
working against nature. And I'll go into
that in a bit more detail in in in a
little while.
So
basically
people always come up and ask me like
what's the solution
and the easiest response generally is
there's no one solution.
Um, from what we found, it's a
combination of solutions. And when you
put all these different, you know,
physical structures and strategies
together, that's when things start
working. So, for example, this image
you're looking at is on the Gold Coast,
and you say like, well, what's the
solution here? But in reality, this
coastline's like carefully curated and
very heavily managed to look like this.
Even though it looks relatively natural,
um it's very much artificial and
man-made. So, um the June system that
you see there was actually put there.
It's built um it's managed. There's a
buried seaw wall that goes under the
June system. We have various types of uh
sand management strategies ensuring that
the beach stays wide like this. We also
use different types of structures like
artificial reefs which I'll go into in
in a little while too. But the the
concept here is that you know it's not
one thing that gets this end result.
It's a series of things and not just
physical things but also like layers of
strategies that go in. So what what I'm
talking about here in this talk is um
the concept of resilience. And so,
um, there's kind of been like an
interest in the use of this word coastal
resilience. And then when you think
about what does resilient actually mean,
you know, resilient means to be able to
take a hit but bounce back. And so what
we're saying here is, you know, we don't
want to necessarily stop all erosion
from happening. We don't necessarily
want to keep all of the, you know, the
coastal processes out from where our
site is. We want to let the natural
processes take place. We just want to
reduce them down. But at the same time,
we want to increase our ability to
recover. So when we say coastal
resilience, we're talking about being
able to take a hit but actually bounce
back rather than avoid the hit
altogether.
And we say this because I mean you most
sandy coastlines naturally are fairly
resistant by default. Um there's like a
natural resilience element built into it
where you know if you have like a
sandune system you know during a storm
event those sandunes might erode and
then make their way back out into the
storm bar. Then over time those stormb
bars sort of work their way back into
shore and the whole system sort of stays
fairly dynamic. But we're just sort of
highlighting here that you know left to
its own devices natural sandy beaches
can actually be quite resilient just by
themselves.
But it's when things start to change
that um you know the whole condition
starts to change. So you know we have
environmental changes that um ultimately
change that natural resilience process
as well as you know human influence
changes like the coastline doesn't
matter if it goes back and forth but
once you start putting structures in
there then you have a hard line then it
does matter if the coastline goes back
and forth. So these are just saying like
if you did if we left nature to do its
thing you know it would not naturally
sort of settle itself out but because
the conditions are changing you know we
have to take it from a different
approach.
Um this is just a term I'm not sure if
you guys use it coastal squeeze
but um it's basically meaning you know
as we
uh as society are building you know
closer and closer to the shoreline
um you know as sea level rise comes up
we're basically getting this kind of
squeezed in um effect happening all
along the coastlines around the world.
And this was actually what the Gold
Coast um looked like some years ago.
Um so, you know, not everywhere in
Australia is doing the kinds of work
that we're doing here on the Gold Coast.
This example on the left is in the state
of uh New South Wales, which is the
state um south of where we are in
Queensland. And it's just this slide is
just highlighting that the difference
between a kind of reactive approach
rather than a proactive approach. So the
example on the left here showing that
the same stretch of coastline in 1978
looks the same as it does now because
basically they wait till the storm
season comes you know try to do some
immediate you know emergency repair
rather than the example on the right
hand side which is where we are here on
the Gold Coast which um basically has
this proactive management of the
coastline you know kind of staying ahead
head of um you know the situation as
storm levels increase and then as
everything increases just being
proactive to sort of stay ahead of it.
And so the same co the two different
coastlines you know 40 years apart look
very different because of the way that
they've been managed.
Uh and then this is just talking a
little bit about how I said you know the
different approaches to managing the
coastline of working you know in the
natural world verse working sort of with
the natural systems. And so when we talk
about resilience like when we're saying
we're not necessarily trying to avoid
erosion or avoid natural processes from
from happening. We're just trying to
dampen those. So you can see like the
you know the history of coastal
engineering as a whole really came from
civil engineering and which really came
from you know ports and harbors where
the aim of ports and harbors was really
to keep the natural processes out so
that you had this nice calm um waterway
you know on the inside of your
structures to so you could you know
maintain travel and trade and and the
functionality of ports. And then that
sort of mindset then shifted to, you
know, coastlines where can we take that
same approach that we use in ports and
harbors and try to control
um or change the natural processes to
get the shoreline to do what we want it
to do. And then the the kind of approach
that we've adopted here on the Gold
Coast is you know another step ahead to
saying like rather than um you know
manipulate the coastal process can we
actually just let the natural processes
take place but just sort of reduce them
and dampen them.
Not to say that you know one of these is
better or worse than the other. It
really depends on the you know the
outcome on the site and what you were
trying to achieve what the goals of the
project are. You know in some instances
you know maybe groins and
breakwateraters are you know the right
option for that site. We're just saying
here that you know these are some of the
things that we've been doing um here on
the Gold Coast and other places around
the world. And just to give an example
like this is one um stretch of coastline
in the UAE where we did a project. So
the example on the left
is uh like an an emergent um breakwater.
It's really just one long stretch. So
there was a design that went in on this
coastline. And you can see basically
that's designed specifically to keep all
of the wave energy out. is designed to
make sure that that beach is, you know,
doesn't move at all. Where, you know, on
the very same stretch of coastline,
we had a a client that wanted to have a
stable beach, but also wanted to be able
to look out to the sea and not have
interrupted views. So, we did this
submerged structure in front of the
properties and basically were able to in
this instant um you know through our
design approach able to say like you
could have a submerged structure and
still have guaranteed beach stability
behind it. And in this example, you
know, I think in we we said something
like an 8-year stable beach guarantee
behind this submerged structure. Um so,
we were able to do that and achieve
that. I'm just just trying to highlight
here that, you know, there's different
ways that you can go about the same
thing and try to like protect a
coastline on the same stretch of
coastline. Um either by, you know,
keeping everything out or by, you know,
letting things in but just in a dampened
sort of approach.
Um, and just to give you a little more
context about how our approach really
began and where things kicked off, it
was here back in on the Gold Coast
during the 60s and 70s. So these scenes
that you're seeing on the right hand
side,
these are the scenes from the 60s and
70s where we had a cyclone event come
through and basically you know destroyed
the coastline, houses falling in, um you
know, roads falling into the sea. Um so
the Gold Coast basically made a decision
back then like we don't want to let this
happen again. So what can we start doing
to prevent you know this from you know
occurring over and over again. So this
is really where things on the go gold go
co started to change and the mentality
shifted into you know how can we be more
proactive so that this doesn't happen
again. Um but you can see like this
image with the car like um people were
dumping cars over the over the cliff to
try to like stop erosion. So it was all
just a bit chaotic.
U and then just to give you sort of
where the follow on from that is you
know we had these significant storm
events um during the 60s and 70s and
then the first sort of point of call was
to do mass nourishment and put all the
sand back that had left. But once you
try to just put sand on the beach
um in a zone that's fairly active, like
the sand didn't really stay. It didn't
last. It just put sand up on top of the
beach and the sand kind of washed out
again. So then like the mentality had to
shift again. Okay, what what can we do
here that's a little bit different?
And this is when, you know, the Gold
Coast really started to come up with
some innovative ways to try to mitigate,
you know, that serious um nourishment
loss. coming up with different ways to
do dredging and nourishment. Coming up
with new systems to pump sand, coming up
with um you know new um breakwater types
um such as you know multifunctional
reefs and dune systems to try to retain
the beach in the most natural way
possible.
And just to give you an example, so just
a few months ago, we got hit by another
cyclone of a similar magnitude to the
one, you know, 50 or 60 years ago. Um,
it was the first time in, you know, 50
years that the Gold Coast has been hit
with a cyclone again since those 60s and
70s ones. And you can see the
difference, you know, between in the 60s
where a cyclone came and, you know,
houses and roads were falling into the
sea and this time, you know, a cyclone
came. We had 15 uh meter waves recorded
offshore here on the Gold Coast just a
few months ago. So 15 m is fairly
significant. It's about as big as it's
ever gotten here. And I guess what we're
showing here is, you know, the beaches
did see some erosion, yes. But those
June systems that have been put in place
and managed over the decades kind of did
their job, you know, by taking the brunt
of the storm event and stopping the
erosion from coming all the way back and
houses falling into the sea. But it's
not just the June system. is like the
you know the sand management practices
that have been under undertaking for the
last few decades etc etc. So all of the
systems combined basically were you know
put under this stress test just a few
months ago and this is a you know a
pretty good outcome I think um compared
to you know the cyclone from you know 50
60 years ago.
So when we talk about um resilience,
we're really talking about a framework
here. And so our approach to, you know,
a new site or a new project is we we try
to break up into these three sort of
main categories where we talk about, you
know, the bottom of the beach. And by
the bottom of the beach, I mean anything
that you can't see. So, you know, when
people talk about the beach, they
generally think about, you know, the
sand up on the top of beach that you
see, but the beach actually goes out
quite a long way. There's like an active
system that goes out, you know, deep
into the water. So, you really have to
consider all the way out. Um, here on
the Gold Coast, for example, we have a
depth of closure at like minus 20 m. So,
you know, there's active um sand
movement when you're standing on the
beach and you're looking out for, you
know, 100 or so meters. There's still
active sand all the way out there. So,
when you're trying to do these kind of
coastal resilience projects, like you
can't not think about what's happening
underwater all the way out in that
active zone. Uh then we have the top of
the beach. This is the area that you can
see.
Um, and then a big one, obviously we're
here, we're talking about like the
sediment supply or sand supply, like
sand coming in and out of the system.
Um, I think this is a really integral
part of the puzzle that often gets
overlooked. So, yeah, I'll go into these
again bit more detail. So when we're
talking about the top of the beach, you
know, these are the kinds of things that
we're talking about like nourishment,
um, June restoration, but we're also
talking about, you know, terminal
structures. So structures that are
actually permanently buried and really
just a last line of defense in those
kind of worst case cyclonic events. So
for 99% of the time, you don't actually
see them. You just know that they're
there.
Um,
for example, you know, this is basically
a cross-section of what we have here.
So, we actually build these um boulder
walls all the way down the coastline.
Um, this is our last line of defense.
This is, you know, what
um is the emergency back stop and gives
the city the confidence to be able to
build skyscrapers and, you know,
insurance companies the ability to, you
know, put insurance against all of these
buildings, but it's what happens in
front of those seaw walls. So this is
the the the dune system and the
management of the June system and the
constant you know monitoring and
maintenance of those June systems that
are really taking the hit of these
cyclonic events. This is just an example
of um like an artificial headland that's
sticking out and um you can't see it
nowadays for the most part because it's
buried under the sand. Um, but it's just
a way, you know, of manipulating that
top of the beach. When we talk about the
bottom of the beach, you know, every
site's different and every depth of
closure is different. Um, I'm not sure
if the the term depth of closurees
um, you know, really that well known,
but the depth of closure basically means
the depth at which, you know, the bottom
of the beach stops being active. So it
could be different for um you know the
areas that you're talking about. But I
said like here the depth of closure for
us is way out. So you know we have to
consider what's happening in the in the
surf zone you know 100 meters off the
beach.
And this is where we do things like um
you know nearshore nourishment which
I'll talk a little bit about plus the
artificial reefs.
So this is a project um that was done
here on the Gold Coast almost 20
something years ago.
So the purpose of this structure was
really to be a twofold um one was to
enhance you know coastal protection.
one was to create um a surf destination
and kind of a byproduct of that was
actually like it became an ecological
hotspot.
So the concept here is that
um you know by having a large footprint
relatively you know shallow but still
submerged at all times taking out you
know a big chunk of that wave energy to
reduce the wave impacts on shore but it
actually acts um as a bit of an
underwater sand trap. So for this
example on the Gold Coast, we have uh a
south to north long shore transport, a
huge volume. So there's about half a
million cubic meters of sand that makes
its way up the Gold Coast every year. So
this offshore structure, while it's
submerged, it kind of acts like a bit of
an underwater groin, almost like an
underwater control structure. So it
helps to build up sand on the um on the
southern end and just create a bit of a
wider buffer beach at that location.
Um
this particular reef, yeah, you can see
you know the G coast is a long stretch
of beach and you know the the the area
of you know effectiveness of this reef
is relatively small. The reason that it
was put here in this specific location
is because this is like a really
vulnerable position right where the road
comes um right out to the beach is
called narrow neck. So this structure
was actually built using large scale
geoexile containers. So big geo tubes.
So you can see the image on the bottom
of the screen bottom left there. That's
actually an image of the barge.
So there's a basically called a split
hopper barge. And inside of that split
hopper, um we rolled out these large geo
tubes. So they're about 20 m long, about
5 to 6 m wide, and they can fill up, you
know, about 2 m high. So they're about
about 300 ton when they're full of sand.
And basically this barge was able to um
you know maneuver, pick up the sand off
the seabed, fill these sandbags, get to
the location that it needed to with GPS
and drop the sandbags on top of each
other to create this, you know, big
artificial structure. So you can see in
the top picture there, basically what
it's doing is just breaking waves
slightly offshore to reduce that wave
energy slightly by the time it comes and
hits the coastline.
Um, this particular reef, it was called
a multi-purpose artificial reef. So, you
know, a bit of design went into the way
that the reef was actually shaped so
that waves when waves broke across it,
you could actually um surf on the reef
itself. The Gold Coast has a really big
surfing culture. And so, not um
disrupting any kind of surfing practices
along the coastline was a really
important KPI for this project. And so
the reefs actually um
shaped differently than you would a
traditional breakwater which is more
shore um parallel. This is almost more
shore perpendicular so that when the
wave comes across it actually has time
to break. So these um this material
actually over time
um you know created a ecological hot
spot because of the geocontainers are
relatively soft and they had this kind
of furry
um exterior. The furry exterior kind of
acted like a almost like a Velcro for
floating microorganisms. So any kind of
microorganisms that were floating in the
general area basically got stuck to it
and yeah it created this kind of
ecological hot spot which actually being
ended up being a bit of a demise because
it became too good of an ecological hot
spot. There was too many fish going
there and it attracted basically too
many fishermen going and the the reef
gets covered in fishermen on calm days
and fishermen drop their anchors and
they can actually um damage these
containers. So this was basically the
the first um of its kind of its scale
and it was really sort of a the pilot
project, the the the guinea pig which we
learned a whole lot of lessons from here
on the Gold Coast which then went into
um like a a second um phase uh which was
a smaller rock reef also built on the
Gold Coast with a slightly different
um
KPI. This one was more surfing focused,
but the idea being similar to sort of
take out some of the wave energy
offshore and to act as a underwater
groin or underwater control structure to
help um you know try to trap some of the
long shore drift, some of the long shore
sand that's moving up the coastline to
create a bit of an offshore buffer.
Um so two very different approaches here
with different materials. You know,
obviously building any kind of um
structure out of rock is significantly
more expensive, but it's also
significantly more durable and stable.
Um so it's a bit of a trade-off. Also,
when you're surfing on it, the the geo
tube reef, um, when you fall off, cuz
you do fall off, um, which I've fallen
off quite a few times and hit the reef,
um, it's quite soft, so it's not not a
bad place to land. So, there's a bit of
public safety that comes into the
equation, too. So somewhere between you
know coastal structure, coastal amenity,
environmental hotspot and um you know
then you got public safety in there and
cost obviously and constructibility. So
it's a it's an interesting um mix. But
you know obviously the thing to remember
when you start to put a coastal control
structure below the water line you get
more wave energy going across it. So
it's obviously not as effective as a
fully emergent breakwater. So once you
start getting submerged, then you get
into the conversation of, you know,
maintenance.
How much sand do you need to, you know,
maintain the system? Because you're not
keeping all the wave energy out. You're
sort of allowing some wave energy to
come in. So you're assuming some kind of
um erosion that's going to take place.
And so what we're trying to do is create
a balance between um you know usability
cost capital cost versus maintenance
cost of how much maintenance needs to be
done
where which is where this concept of
nearshore nourishment comes in. So when
we do um nourishment here on the Gold
Coast for example,
we do some nourishment we put up on the
top of the beach which is the dry sand
that you see. But a lot of most of the
nourishment actually that we do we put
into this nearshore zone which is you
know the bottom of the beach or the area
below the water. So the reason we do
this is for a couple of um key key
reasons. One is it's significantly
cheaper
to put sand um in the nearshore zone
than it is to put it up onto the beach
itself.
um it's less disruptive to the beach
users
and um the quality of the sand that you
put in that nearshore zone can actually
be less.
So the the theory here is when you put
the sand in this nearshore zone,
um the wave energy actually helps to
push the sand onto the beach itself. And
so the natural process is kind of doing
the work for you. So you're essentially
like recreating the stormb bar that
would be there, but you're, you know,
accelerating the natural processes and
allowing that sort of natural storm bar
to make its way back in onto the beach.
So you're kind of nourishing it from the
bottom rather than from the top. So it's
not to say that you have to do one or
the other, but we do these in
conjunction. And it's just part of the
way that the Gold Coast beaches have
been managed and you know part of the
reason that the you know the the sand
system held up so well during you know
cyclonic events. So
which takes me into the last point which
is you know talking about the sand
sediment supply and the sentiment
management. So, um, another thing that
we kind of worked into our system here
on the Gold Coast is something called a
sand bypass and a sand backpass system.
So as sand, you know, naturally makes
its way in our case from south to north,
we're able to, you know, manipulate it
with a pipe network,
um, which can, you know, pick up sand in
one location and actually spit it across
through permanent pipe system to another
location.
This gives us the ability to, you know,
have a really good sand management
system and um, you know, able to
understand, you know, where the sand is
moving and how we can move it back or
forth depending on what we need. We also
integrated a whole heap of, you know,
sand management policies. This was
really important back in the late 80s.
for example like any kind of
uh construction that's done within a you
know I believe it's a
100 meter or could could be 250 m you
know distance of the beach any sand
that's excavated to do you know put in a
new building or you know do any kind of
construction that sand you know by you
know mandate has to go onto the beach
obviously has to be screened first to
make sure it's not contaminated, but any
basically any development that happens
along the coastline, if there's any
excavation that's happening, that sand
we use back onto the beach. So,
integrating these kind of different
policies
um to really encourage, you know,
building up the sand volume, managing
the sand volume. Um that's what's really
working here. Here's just an example of
the bypassing system on the Gold Coast.
So, this is right down the southern end.
Um, if you're looking at the screen, we
have sand that naturally sort of makes
its way from the south and would have
naturally come around that point. But
since um the you know the river entrance
built these big training walls, it
basically blocked that sand from coming
around and the sand on the northern end
was starved and all of the beaches up
the Gold Coast basically were starved of
sand. So what you're seeing in the
bottom right hand corner is a sand
pumping station which is basically a
um a long pier and it has a series of
jet pumps on the end of it. And so as
the sand naturally makes its way from
south to north, the sand's picked up in
those jet pumps and actually pumped
across
um the river entrance over to the
beaches on the north to basically
replicate what would have happened
naturally if that river system um didn't
have the big breakwater training walls
in place. So it's, you know, using these
kinds of um sand management strategies
and technologies that's enabled the Gold
Coast to be able to integrate this sort
of holistic um approach. And then when
you put put them all together, that's
when you start getting the the outcomes
that we have, you know, like integrating
the sand source from, you know, pump
networks. Um, putting in reef systems,
um, building up the sand bars in the
nearshore area with nearshore
nourishment, and then putting the June
system up on the top of the beach, but
not just putting the dunes there, like
actually monitoring, managing those June
systems as well is when you really start
to get things um, come together. Aon we
have maybe one more minute and then we
need to wrap and move on for some
questions.
>> Okay, great. So this is basically um you
know the process of coastal resilience
in a nutshell
and I just got some really quick
examples of you know some different
things we're doing around the world.
This is a place in California at the
moment. you know, rather than a
traditional groin field, we're looking
at doing these short rounded sort of
headlands. Um, so rather than groins
which, you know, stop that natural
process um going up, these allow the
natural long shore transport to happen
just in a slower sort of way.
Um, this is just an example of like a
nearshore break order that we did but on
a really smaller scale rather than
having large ones. So, you know, you can
create um you know, small differences in
the coastline rather than big extreme
ones. Because you guys were talking
about cliffs before I threw this in,
this is just an example of um you know,
a a cliff system here in Queensland. Um
you know, as a claybased cliff that was
falling into the sea. We we built this
sort of um over uh shock creek wall down
the bottom of it, just what you can see
along the base.
um just to stop that cliff erosion from
going in.
And these might look like a typical
grind, but they're actually made out of
um five ton sandbags. And the reason we
did them at a 5 ton sandbags and not
rock is because the um it's a really
popular community beach and they like to
sit and walk out on those sandbags and
sit on them. Um this one actually we had
to re um you know redo the the job at
the end of the the project's lifespan
and the community actually wanted to
have the sandbags instead of rocks. So
there's different things you can do.
Here's just another example. or you know
this is a a breakwater niche or
breakwater using um geo tubes rather
than rocks just because the the KPIs and
you know the end result they wanted um
the users to be able to like walk along
it and and and um access them and that's
basically it in a nutshell. There's just
a couple of examples of you know some
other things that that you can do.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much. Um is
there someone wants to ask our own
questions?
I would
>> I have a question.
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> I should I should go ahead. Okay. Yeah.
Um I'm interested in the regulations. Uh
Erin, if you could say a few words about
maybe um when projects are
uh approved, is there something that uh
um makes the interpreneur, the project
um owner do certain things in the
future? For example, we also have the
south to north sediment transport issue.
And we've had like large marinas built
that have
um caused the accumulation of sand on on
the southern side and the loss of sand
in the north. And that has uh required
the building of breakwaters.
Yeah.
>> And the the interpreter who built that,
the proponent had absolutely no um
um authority, no um requirement to make
amends or to be involved in the
protection of the northern beach. So I'm
wondering what kind of regulations you
have in with that with regard to the
future of this um blocking of the sand
over time.
Yeah. Yeah, that's a great question.
Um, we got pretty strict rules here in
Australia and and we're doing, you know,
the works in California at the moment,
too. Um so just for example the the
project in California it's a very
similar situation where a huge um marina
was put in back in the60s
I believe and it basically created a
whole heap of pro problems down drift.
Um so you know we're going back now to
try to you know
fix problems that were created you know
50 years ago. So there's no real way to,
you know, completely eradicate the
problem because the problem's already
there now. So it's only a matter of like
looking forward into the future unless
you were to go back and, you know, fully
remove the marina. Um, one of the things
that's probably the easiest way in a
situation like that where you know
there's a a definite
a unidirectional long shore transport
and there's a significant you know
man-made structure that's gone in and
disrupting the natural processes is
probably to have some kind of
backpassing system
um the pump pump system you know and I'm
not too sure like who owns the marina
who operates it But you know maybe it
becomes the ownership of the you know
that particular
structure um you know if it's if it's
known or if it's been able to show that
you know because of this it's causing
problems down here. Therefore you know
to mitigate those problems we need to
backpass sand that's you know being
blocked or sorry bypass sand that's
being blocked. And that's a really, you
know, not a super complicated process
because, you know, if the sand was
naturally going from south to north and
it's kind of getting blocked by a big
structure, then by putting a pump system
on the one side and essentially just
pumping it across, then you're allowing
that system to take place. But I'm not
sure who like how you can say who would
be responsible for that. Um because, you
know, it's a kind of a historic um
project rather than a new project.
>> Right. Right. Yeah. No, I'm just
wondering if the newer ones now if
there's something in Australia at least
that requires that uh responsibility
over time but
>> okay definitely
>> basically we have to do any kind of
coastal structure here you know that you
you've got to do like environmental
impacts and you know coastal studies and
um yeah you essentially have to be able
to prove that whatever the the structure
or implementation that you're doing here
is not going to have a negative effect
down drift or If it is, how are you
going to mitigate that? Um, so yeah,
basically nothing here or you know in in
California where we're doing the prote.
So um yeah, 100% there's the regulation
in place.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, one quick more question from Mayan
that voted very nice.
>> Good morning. Thank you for uh the very
interesting presentation. I'm interested
uh to ask about the the quantity of
sand. It seems like uh some of these
solution require lots of sand and they
require a maintenance of annual sand uh
nourishment. So let's say for the go
coast for 1 kilometer of coastline what
is the quantity the annual quantity of
sand required to maintain these
solutions and where does it come from?
What is the source?
>> Uh so we have a couple of sources. One
is like the the natural long shore
transport that comes from the south to
north. So like I said, we have about
there's about half a million cubic
meters of sand naturally coming into the
system and basically going through the
system every year. So we um able to
basically take at the moment we pump
back so from it goes from the south all
the way to the north and we pump back
about 80,000 cubes of that as needed.
So, um, that's basically what the, you
know, we've allowed as a as a as a
coastal community to say like we're if
we if we need it, we can pump back about
80,000 cubes, but we also have sand that
comes from um offshore sources. So, we
have offshore sand stock piles. We also
have sand we have like this waterway
system. Um it's like a sandy bed
internal waterway system um that we take
sand from because it gets infilled from
the ocean every year. So we take it from
that basically to do maintenance for
like the river entrances and we use that
as well. So for a 1 kilometer strip on
the Gold Coast, what's the volume? I
mean annually it depends on the
location. like we have some areas that
are hot spots and some areas that don't
get maintained at all. So towards the
northern end just because of the way our
coastline's shaped and because that's
where the main tourist destination is.
Um I believe you know you're probably
looking at somewhere around 40,000 cubes
a year over a 5 km sort of space. So if
you did that what's that?
you know that that's the kind of numbers
that we're talking about and that's
without in that particular spot there's
no actual structure. So that's just
putting sand, you know, maintaining the
system.
The areas further down south with the
structures um get a lot less.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much everyone.
Your details is on the screen now. So if
everyone wants to get in touch.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Thank you for your
presentation. Okay.
[Music]
of
Uhchech.
[Music]
foreign.
TV.
foreign
[Music]
speech.
form.
[Music]
Australia.
foreign.
[Music]
Never mind.
[Applause]
forefront.
for
[Music]
ongoing.
Brazil 11.
forch.
Will are you here with us?
>> I am. Good morning.
>> This is you.
>> All right. Good morning everybody and
thank you John for the introduction. Um
so building on what John has been
talking about. Um I wanted to start by
explaining one of Seaell's central
objectives. Uh we as a company
fundamentally want to build reefs that
are as natural as possible. We certainly
don't want to use concrete and we want
to use as little steel as possible
within our structures. So instead we set
out to form a skeleton and then we use
um natural mater materials where we can
and also minerals available to us in the
sea to build out the reefs and then
ideally or ultimately what we're trying
to do is encouraging reef building
organisms like oysters, muscles um and
ultimately corals to form the structure
itself and then they then perform a
lasting long-term solution.
So as an example of some of the research
that we're doing um this slide shows uh
laboratory results and also some field
trials we've been doing with Bath
University here in the UK over the last
couple of years where we've developed a
technique to grow rock from minerals in
the sea across bamboo. Okay. And just to
explain a little bit how this works, I
mean the bamboos receive some special
sort of treatments which I won't go
into, but we pass a small electrical
current through the seawater and that
causes the pH around the bamboo around
the structure to increase. So it becomes
more alkaline and that causes minerals
that are in abundance in the ocean to
crystallize out and form a rock. And if
you if you do this for long enough and
you do it in the right way, you can form
a rock that's as hard as concrete. But
this crucially that rock is also ideal
for marine life and that's you know what
we're we're we want to attach to our
structures and then develop them
forward. So next slide Jonathan.
Now before um sorry now in this project
this is um you know continuing with
these sort of field trials um we
installed just five units um about 10
mters long about 100 meters offshore and
you can see in the picture on the left
we've installed bamboo around the outer
edge around the ocean edge of these
reefs and within literally a couple of
weeks um and this photo is taken about a
month afterwards you could see the
direct impact that that those structures
were having on the shoreline. So the
area I've marked in red. Okay. And in
the following months, you then saw that
area in med sort of um broaden out and
extend towards us in within that
photograph. Now essentially what we've
done is we've installed with just 10
mters of reef, we've enhanced about 200
mters of shoreline and we could install
those structures in an afternoon. Okay.
It's a very fast process um of you know
essentially achieving long-term um
protection. Now next slide Jonathan.
Now before we start um any project and
the you know the last presenter to
touched on this as well um you have to
understand what the marine environment
is doing. You know you need to
understand what's what the waves and
currents within any area are doing. So
we always start any project with a
thorough examination of of any available
data. Obviously we need to understand
the local beyimemetry and sort of
historical changes but we also then
collect all of the available wave and
current data for a region and we build
what we call a multivariate stochcastic
model. So this con this looks at effects
of wave height, wave direct uh sorry
wave um height, wave period and
direction simultaneously
and it allows us to simulate um
thousands even hundreds of thousands of
years also taking into account things
like hurricans and also climate change.
Next slide John.
And from each of those simulations, we
build out in a sort of clever way, we
then simulate the the local wave
conditions or what we call wave induced
currents. Um, now it's those currents
that are affected or or essential for
the movement of sediment around a
shoreline. So, where you see um currents
slowing down, you're likely to see
sediment being deposited. If you see
those currents moving offshore, they're
going to take sand away from your beach
and deposit deposited offshore. And it's
managing those currents that um is
essentially crucial to effective coastal
management.
Um now alongside that um we've invested
a lot of time and e effort um with MCC
support on this as well um to understand
the direct effect of the individual
reefs on the waves that are coming past.
So this is laboratory testing that we
did at Imperial College. Um and this is
looking at the you know obviously the
impact of the of the reef on the on the
waves going past. This is an earlier
reef design um that we used to use and
on top of this simulation we
superimposed the CFD results and you can
see an almost I mean if you look at the
surface there's an almost perfect
correlation between the two which is
which is which is important. Um but what
the CFD allows us to understand is how
the flow or the water is flowing around
the structure but also allows us to
calculate the pressures on the structure
and this in turn allows us to then go
back and optimize those structures
numerically. Yeah. Um laboratory work is
slow laborious and quite costly.
Obviously if we can calibrate our CFD
models we can then make a number of
iterative improvements and that's really
what's led to our sort of latest design.
So the next next slide Jonathan.
So,
so we've taken our sort of CFD results
and then we've coupled that with an FN
model and we've looked at over the years
probably about 50 different types of
structures and it's almost became a game
within the company to come up with a new
structure every week. Okay. And we've
we've finalized on what we're calling
these hyperbolid structures. So, it's
the the image you see on the right. Now,
hyperboloids actually appear quite a lot
in in engineering. Um they were first
invented by the Ukrainians um for as a
lighthouse tower, but you nowadays see
them as the cooling towers for a lot of
power stations. They also the the base
of an awful lot of water towers. Um so
once you look out for them, they appear
all over the place. But what's clever
about them is they are made up of
straight elements. So all of those lines
you see in that in that in that picture
are all completely straight. So it means
manufacturing becomes a lot easier. And
I can also use a wide variety of
different materials within these so long
as they're broadly straight. And you
know, taking the CFD results, we get the
pressures out of there and we use that
to actually model the deflections and
the forces on that structure. And
crucially, we also use it to model the
um the the anchoring that's necessary
for these structures when we first
install them. Over time, these units are
supposed to thicken out. They'll build
up at rock, but they'll also then build
out with an awful lot of marine life. So
they their actual natural weight will
hold them in position but initially you
need some good anchoring to um funnel to
to to survive.
Uh final slide Jonathan.
Um so this is really coming back to a
picture that Jonathan showed earlier but
this is the the latest reefs uh actually
the largest reefs that we've installed
to date um with MCC support. Um, and
what we did here is we divided the reef
into broadly sort of two sections, but
you've you can see the sort of the three
well there's four rings, but there's
three sections going vertically. Now, we
couldn't get bamboo in um in Israel. Um,
so we've ended up using a willow
material um similar to what they put
around uh you might put around your
garden to sort of protect against the
wind. Um, and that's in the top two
sections. In the bottom section, we
deliberately leave that open because
what we want to do a is to allow fish an
area where they can come in and out. Um,
in addition, we are worried about scour.
So that bottom zone is actually left
free. So you the water can near near the
sea floor can move freely forward and
backwards. Um, reducing any sort of
effects of scour which again will I
didn't catch the word uh for the two top
layers. What did you say? It's not
bamboo. What is it?
>> We've used a willow.
>> Willow. Okay. Thanks.
>> I mean, we've been experimenting with
different materials, but um bamboo and
willow at the moment seem to like the
best contenders, but it it doesn't have
to be those materials. It could be other
things. Um so, Jonathan, back to you to
finish.
>> Okay, thank you.
forchech.
[Music]
But forale.
Kevin
forchech.
[Music]
Shooters.
Yeah.
[Music]
Shal.
Okay.
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
forgot.
foreign.
[Applause]
for
him. Shalom.
butch.
I will ask in English for the benefit of
the first speaker
in regards to the Gold Coast which I
also know uh the recent strong storm
that uh occurred
uh you claimed that uh you had uh some
projects there. I believe I know uh many
of uh the the uh constructions and uh
protections there. But could you uh
indicate us what is the effect uh on the
sectors that uh your company uh made the
protection means? Thank you.
>> Okay.
Um, so we do all kinds of stuff from,
you know, all of the
basically the seaw walls up and down the
Gold Coast.
So most of the seaw walls weren't
exposed really.
One of the the main things that happened
was, you know, there was a loss of
sand
um in front of the main area at Surface
Paradise, which is like the tourist um
location.
And for the most part of the Gold Coast,
basically everything's constructed
behind the seaw wall. So if you lose any
of the um if you lose any of the June
system basically nothing's really
affected. So nothing structurally is
affected. Um but there was this one
section of surface paradise where they
have built it out into the beach
like a concrete platform. Um that became
exposed
during the cyclone.
So, we went in for the local council and
basically determined that it needed some
sort of emergency protection
um at the base because nobody nobody
knew uh how deep the structure actually
went. Is it like basically like a
concrete vertical wall?
Um so, we ended up putting in some um
emergency scour protection along the
base of that.
I understand there was been very severe
erosion all along the the Golden Coast
uh area.
>> Uh yes. So like I said in the image
before you can see like a lot of the go
so the go coast is like 45 km long.
So we had this section up the northern
end. Um it's probably about four
kilometers that got um you know severely
eroded right in front of where the
tourist location is for the most part of
the Gold Coast. Basically the June
systems still in place.
Um
>> thank you.
>> I would like to thank all of the PE all
of the speakers. Thank you Victoria Aron
Elan will Jonathan.
We encourage everyone to keep in touch
with us. And that's it.
[Music]
Thank